Amir Masood Baghi

Uppsala, Sweden

■ +46 73 971 61 88 | Maintenance | Github.com/amirbaghi | Inkedin.com/in/amir-masoud-baghi | Inkedin.com/in/amir-masoud-baghi

Currently a computer science Master's student at Uppsala University, I have a strong interest in both machine learning and game development. With a solid foundation in these areas, I aim to participate in research-oriented activities towards developing AI (or non-AI) approaches to practical problems, such as those found in the development of games. In addition, I enjoy exploring art, philosophy, and overall programming, which helps broaden my perspective and enhance my creative thinking.

Education

Uppsala University Uppsala, Sweden

Master of Science In Computer Science

Fall 2022 - Current

- Passed with distinction in all completed courses.
- Recipient of the Uppsala University International Scholarship Fund for the second year.

Shiraz University Shiraz, Iran

Bachelor's Program In Computer Engineering

Fall 2018 - Fall 2022

• Ranked 662nd in the National Entrance Exam (among 144,000 applicants).

• Finished in four years with an 18.56/20 CGPA. Ranked 2nd among the 81 students of my class.

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents Asadpour High School

Bandar Abbas, Iran

2014 - 2018

Mathematics-Physics Diploma

Graduated with 19.28/20 CGPA.

Work Experience

Electronic Arts, SEED Stockholm, Sweden

Master's Thesis Intern

Jan 2024 - Current

- Currently working on my master's thesis as an intern in the SEED research team at Electronic Arts.
- Researching the application of modern *multi-agent reinforcement learning* methods in game-AI, in addition to possible improvements to the methods.

Medrick Games Tehran, Iran (Remote)

Unity Game Developer (Internship)

Sept 2021 - Aug 2022

- My team and I made four casual/hyper-casual mobile games among other activities.
- Additionally participated in game design tasks, e.g. idea development and refinement, and marketing activities, e.g. creating one minute videos
 for our games.

Academic Experience ___

Research Intern Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University

Summer 2023 - Winter 2023

 A voluntary research endeavour, I studied the neural compression and novel view synthesis of high-resolution micro-CT imaging using state-ofthe-art methods in the field and implemented a feasible solution to the problem. Supervised by Jens Sjölund.

Teaching Assistant, Various Courses

Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University

Spring 2023 - Current

• Previously Human-Computer Interaction, Combinatorial Optimization, and Statistical Machine Learning. Currently the new instance of Statistical Machine Learning and Reinforcement Learning.

Teaching Assistant, Various Courses

Shiraz, Iran

Shiraz University

Fall 2019 - Spring 2022

· Assisted in various courses including Database Design Principles, Operating Systems Lab, Advanced Programming, and more.

University Projects _____

Neural Compression and Novel View Synthesis of High-Resolution Micro-CT Imaging

Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University - Independent Research Work and Project in Computer Systems Course

Winter 2023

Implicit neural representations (INRs), like CuNeRF and hash-based methods, were used to compress, reconstruct, and render high-resolution 3D micro-CT scans. Implemented using PyTorch. Under supervision of Jens Sjölund and partly Stefanos Kaxiras in the Project In Computer Systems course.

FEBRUARY 17, 2024 1

Learning To Play Pong Using DQN

Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University - Reinforcement Learning Course

Spring 2023

A Deep Q-Network (DQN) was implemented, based on the Nature paper by Mnih et al. (2015), to learn and play the game of Pong (and most Atari games). The network was tested on "Breakout!" successfully as well. Implemented using PyTorch.

Various Classifiers and a DL Model For Lead Role Prediction In Films

Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University - Statistical Machine Learning Course

Spring 2023

Five types of classifiers and a neural network were developed with advanced hyper-tuning for prediction of the lead actor's gender based on a script's attributes. Implemented using PyTorch, RayTune, and scikit-learn. Got a *golden star* in the course.

Advanced Reversi AI Uppsala, Sweden

Uppsala University - Functional Programming I Course

Fall 2022

The game of Reversi (Othello) and an advanced opponent AI were implemented in Haskell. Ranked 3rd in a tournament against other AIs.

Aphrodite, A Covid-19 Detection Application

Shiraz, Iran

Shiraz University - Systems Analysis and Design Course

Fall 2021

Developed a Dockerized COVID-19 detection application for Shiraz hospitals using a pre-trained model (COVIDNet-CT). Utilized Python, Qt C++, Prometheus, Grafana, Node Exporter, and MySQL.

Various Game Development Mini-Projects

Shiraz, Iran

Shiraz University - Computer Games Design and Computer Graphics I Courses

Fall 2020 - Spring 2021

Implemented core game development and graphics concepts, including skeletal animation (inverse kinematics), game engine development, design patterns, game physics, rendering engines, and game metric analysis. Developed using C++ with OpenGL/GLFW/GLUT.

Modo, Bus Transportation App

Shiraz, Iran

I.D.E.A. Footsteps Contest

Summer 2020

For the I.D.E.A. Footsteps Contest, we were tasked with implementing a tracking system for the university's bus lines, including a mobile app to provide users with info on the scheduling. Developed with Flutter. *Ranked 1st in the contest*.

Teatro, Game Console In C Shiraz, Iran

Shiraz University - Principles of Programming Course

Spring 2019

Ilnneala Cuiadan

As the course project, our team implemented a game console to be able to render certain 2D games on PC, written in C. Ranked 2nd in the course.

Awards, Honors, And Certificates_

2023	Completion of SFI (Svenska For Invandrare), Uppsala Kommun	uppsala, Sweden
2023	International Scholarship Fund, Uppsala University	Uppsala, Sweden
2022	Dean's List, Shiraz University	Shiraz, Iran
2021	TOEFL iBT (120/120), ETS	Tehran, Iran
2020	Ranked First In The Technical Footsteps Competition, I.D.E.A Association	Shiraz, Iran
2019	Completion Of A Full Program In English Language, Iran Language Institute	Shiraz, Iran

Skills_

Programming Languages Python, Java, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, Golang, HTML/CSS, MiniZinc, Haskell, GLSL

Game Development Unity, Game Design Patterns
Graphics and GPU Libraries OpenGL, GLUT, GLFW, SDL, CUDA

Web/Application Frameworks Flutter, Vue, Qt, Spring, Django REST, Gin, Bootstrap, Flask

Mathematical and ML Tools PyTorch, Ray, NumPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn

Project Management Agile Software Development (SCRUM), Git, Trello, JIRA

Miscellaneous LTEX, UML Diagrams, Docker, SQL

Completion of SEL/Syangles För Invandrage) Hancala Kammun

Soft Skills Communication, Teamwork, Team Management, Resilience, Perseverance

Interests

Programming / Games and their Development / Art, Music, Film / Artificial Intelligence / Philosophy

Languages_

English Full Proficiency
Farsi Native Proficiency

Swedish Intermediate Proficiency

FEBRUARY 17, 2024